2021

Land-On-Block – Bio and Resume



dApp II - Capstone Project

Pratik Patel

Professor: Dave Mckay & Dhruvin

Parikh

4/23/2021



Bio:



Pratik is FinTech professional with five years of rich experience in finance and insurance sector as Business Analyst. He has done his bachelor's in Information Technology and Master's in Business Administration, which really helps him to dive deep in finance domain along with technical aspects. He has added Blockchain development, a niche domain, learning from George Brown college recently and interested to solve real time issues faced by society in general. He is passionate about learning new technology and loves to wander in trails in free time.

My resume is on next page.

Pratik Patel

Business Analysis | Agile | FinTech | Blockchain

Toronto, ON | Pratik.it007@gmail.com | 437-237-6939 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/pratikit007

Executive Summary

A result-driven FinTech professional with 5 years of experience as **Business Analyst**, mainly in digital transformation projects. Certified Scrum Master having self-starter attitude and rich experience in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), requirement gathering and analysis, developing BRD, facilitating Scrum ceremonies, functional testing, integration of projects and business consulting along with well-developed project management and leadership abilities.

Professional Work Experience

Amazon Canada Fulfillment Services Associate

Brampton, Canada
April 2020 to present

- Collaborated with internal stake holders to investigate and prevent customer dissatisfaction by troubleshooting and resolving operational queries with data analysis and reporting
- Identified and evaluated potential risks in operational processes with minimal direction, analyzing data sets and performing data mining
- Utilized database technologies including SQL, Excel and used innovative business intelligence tools such as Kibana to analyze the high volume of data to reduce missing items issues by 7%
- Supported senior management by managing metrics reporting and big data analysis for strategic advice and business forecast

Advanced tech skills and tools: Kibana, SQL, AWS Cloud, Excel S&P Global Market Intelligence (https://www.spqlobal.com)
Business Analyst – II

Ahmedabad, India
Jan 2018 to Feb 2020

- Collaborated with customers, Systems Dev, Strategy teams and other enablement teams across
 the organization to elicit requirements, documenting system requirements, to ensure end-to-end
 specification, scoping of proposed enhancements and release of assigned project deliverables
- Transformed business requirements into epics and user stories for product backlog and actively
 engaged in prioritization of user stories, various scrum ceremonies such as stand up meeting,
 Sprint and release planning, sprint retrospective
- Liaised between business and technical personnel to lead SaaS based financial product development in order to ensure the mutual understanding of process and application
- Managed a collocated team of 14 consisting Devs, QAs, UAT and Product Owner along with cross functional teams to remove impediments, to foster best practices of agile methodology in a team and creating collaborative environment
- Successfully completed i3 India Hackathon project in 12 days with analytical, critical thinking skills that **reduced clone process time by 96%**, and won the "Best Shippable Product" award
- Addressed major and critical production issue of 14,000 incorrect stock price alerts within 48
 hours with my problem solving, attention to details and interpersonal skills
- Assisted developers with custom SQL queries, stored procedures to ease out their development work by 20% and also quality assurance team for System Functional & Integration Testing (SIT)
- Identified and tracked technical delivery milestones, potential risks, changes and dependencies and communicated project requirements and status to respective stakeholders

Administered Level 2 support for customer support escalations with Salesforce CRM, defined an
appropriate course of action for resolution and used those learnings to make the product more
robust with continuous improvement

Advanced tech skills and tools: AWS Cloud, SQL, Salesforce CRM, Azure DevOps, Python, HTML, CSS, JSON, XML, PowerBI, Excel, PowerPoint, Agile

LTI (L&T InfoTech) (https://www.lntinfotech.com)

Pune, India

Associate Business Analyst

Jun 2015 to Dec 2017

- Conducted interviews with multiple stakeholders to capture and create Business Requirements documents (BRDs), created user stories and performed scrum activities
- Extracted data using complex SQL queries and Identified pattern of claims for insurance policy analysis which helped underwriters in their quote making decisions faster by 15 -20%
- Learned American Insurance domain within 2 months in order to support client's product development and enhancement, delivered it for 6 releases with "ZERO" post production bugs
- Compiled data of various categories of insurance and generated reports in MS Access and Excel such as aggregation and pivot for in-depth analysis and reporting purposes
- Performed quality assurance, system integration and user acceptance testing facilitating on time, on budget and acclaimed "go-live" of enterprise implementations for client
- Mentored and coached junior analysts in cross-functional teams for collaborative environment
- Automated test scenarios of creating and editing insurance policies of various categories to expedite the testing which resulted in a reduction in testing time by 60% to 65%
- Presented PowerPoint presentations to senior management for project implementation, progress and metrics reporting and strategic advice for business needs
- Actively involved in solution advisory/consulting for client business needs and business processes **Advanced tech skills and tools:** Jira, Excel, Python, XML, PowerBI, PowerPoint, MS Visio

Education

George Brown College- Canada	2020 - 2021
Post Graduate Certificate- Blockchain Development – FinTech	
Pandit Deendayal Petroleum University - India	2013 - 2015
Master of Business Administration-Finance & Operation	
Gujarat Technological University - India	2008 - 2012
Bachelor of Engineering – Information Technology	
Certifications	
Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Power BI by Microsoft	2020
Querying data with Transact-SQL by Microsoft	2020
Certified Cloud Practitioner by Amazon Web Services	2019
Certified Scrum Master CSM® by Scrum Alliance	2018
AINS 24 Certified by Associate in General Insurance by (The Institutes)	2015
ISTQB Certified by Indian Testing Board	2015
CP-BAT Certified by Agile Testing Alliance	2015
> FLIP certified in the course of "Trade Finance and Cash Management Service	es" 2014